{
    "id": "f595e546e3ef4a44b95433deec0fcc2e",
    "title": "Degrees of Comparison",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Rahul’s composition is ……………… than that of Rohan.",
            "description": "Better is the comparative form of good.",
            "answers": [
                "better",
                "more good",
                "gooder"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The new mansion is …………………. than the old one.",
            "description": "We make the comparative form of splendid by putting more before it.",
            "answers": [
                "splendid",
                "more splendid",
                "most splendid"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is ………………. than most of her neighbors.",
            "description": "We use a comparative form before than. Wealthier is the comparative form of wealthy.",
            "answers": [
                "wealthy",
                "wealthier",
                "wealthiest"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "It was the ………………… day of my life.",
            "description": "We use a superlative adjective after the. Saddest is the superlative form of sad.",
            "answers": [
                "sad",
                "sadder",
                "saddest"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Gold is more precious than ……………….. metal.",
            "description": "When two objects are compared with each other, the latter term of comparison must exclude the former.",
            "answers": [
                "any",
                "all",
                "any other"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She earns as ………………… as I do.",
            "description": "We use the positive adjective in the structure as…as.",
            "answers": [
                "much",
                "more",
                "most"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He arrived ……………….. than I expected.",
            "description": "Later is the comparative form of late.",
            "answers": [
                "later",
                "latter"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Ours is the ………………. house on this street.",
            "description": "Last can indicate position. Latest cannot express this idea.",
            "answers": [
                "last",
                "later",
                "latest"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "This is the ……………… church in India.",
            "description": "Eldest is only used to speak of people.",
            "answers": [
                "old",
                "older",
                "oldest"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The princess was ………………….. than her brother.",
            "description": "We make the comparative form of courageous with more.",
            "answers": [
                "courageous",
                "more courageous",
                "most courageous"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Mumbai is ……………… from the equator than Chennai.",
            "description": "Farther means more distant. Further means additional.",
            "answers": [
                "farther",
                "further"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        }
    ]
}